<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Best Practice Thoughts</title>
    <link>https://www.gbgconnect.com/t/best-practice-thoughts/43</link>
    <description>Best Practices in my opinion help guide decisions. There may be exceptions but exceptions require additional rationale and critique.

The overall best practice guideline (IMHO) is that **individuals participating in workshop builds (whether 3rd graders, graduate students or corporate event attendees) take PERSONAL RESPONSIBILITY for the cars they modify.**
This practice will result in families, children, tools, cars, event attendees and the event location being treated with compassion, care and consideration.

Other Best Practice thoughts:

1) **Cars and attendance at the &#39;workshops&#39; are free to families.**
There may be circumstances where groups may have to require families to provide the car and/or parts of the modification kit (PVC, pool noodle etc.) but there should not be a &#39;charge&#39; for the actual modifications.
Certain individuals (examples: clinicians, teachers, admin) may
a) be charged a fee for attendance.
b) gain other perks for attendance - example, continuing education units.

2) **A mechanical and/or electrical engineer should &#39;sign off&#39; on the modifications.**

3) **Someone with significant knowledge of each child&#39;s abilities should be present** during the build. In addition to family, teacher and/or pediatric therapist are often helpful.

4) **A group&#39;s initial workshop should be as easy and fun as possible.** 
This means the simplest cars, the less involved children, the fewer the cars and the less stress the better.

5) **Remind families that mobility is risky.**
Both the children and families are gaining meaningful mobility through a modified car.
This mobility may be completely new for them.
A child with a toy car has the ability to move (likely faster, easier and over more ground than ever before) -- so keep a constant eye on the driver!

6) **When in (even the slightest) doubt about something, simply ask**

7) **Have enough extra hands and eyes**
This lessens the stress, increases the fun, gets questions answered and allow each family to be pampered just like they should be!

8) **Consider the liability.**
Different groups address liability differently but all groups should discuss and address the liability of modifying cars.

9) **Use only top quality cars**
please seek out information from the other chapters/groups modifying cars as to which cars are low quality and simply do not use them.

10) **Thank those that share their information, and share what you learn!**
Go Baby Go spreads rapidly due to the time, effort, compassion and skill of those who join the movement.

11) **Go bigger, build better, share broader!**</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 16:58:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Best Practices</category>
    <atom:link href="https://www.gbgconnect.com/t/best-practice-thoughts/43.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Best Practice Thoughts</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[jacgallo]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Phys Occup Ther Pediatr.](<a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/30592238#" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/30592238#</a>) 2018 Dec 28:1-18. doi: 10.1080/01942638.2018.1547808. [Epub ahead of print]</p>
<p>Modified Ride-on Cars as Early Mobility for Children with Mobility Limitations: A Scoping Review.</p>
<p>This study aims to systematically examine and map current available evidence describing the benefits of modified ride-on car use for young children with mobility limitations and identify potential applications to occupational and physical therapy practice while illuminating gaps in knowledge to be explored in future research.</p>
<p>METHODS:</p>
<p>An electronic database search, manual search of bibliographies, contact with existing networks and organizations were used to identify all relevant literature. Studies addressing modified ride-on toy use by children ≤6 years old with identified mobility delays were included. Data were extracted and analyzed independently by the investigators using a standardized process.</p>
<p>RESULTS:</p>
<p>Thirteen case studies and one case controlled study involving children ≤6 years old with a variety of diagnoses were included in the review. Studies were at the activities and participation levels and focused on mobility, interpersonal interactions and relationships, communication, and Community, Social, and Civic Life.</p>
<p>CONCLUSION:</p>
<p>Findings support the use of modified ride-on cars as a form of early mobility to encourage the development of social-emotional and mobility skills in young children with mobility limitations. Future research with valid, reliable outcome measures that address changes in developmental levels across domains is</p>
          <p><a href="https://www.gbgconnect.com/t/best-practice-thoughts/43/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://www.gbgconnect.com/t/best-practice-thoughts/43/3</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 16:58:50 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">www.gbgconnect.com-post-43-3</guid>
        <source url="https://www.gbgconnect.com/t/best-practice-thoughts/43.rss">Best Practice Thoughts</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Best Practice Thoughts</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[jacgallo]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a class="attachment" href="https://global.discourse-cdn.com/standard11/uploads/gbgconnect/original/1X/82a86a86aaab8a423486c6536b899212509d0589.docx" rel="nofollow noopener">Car Robot Harness Bibliography.docx</a> (208.0 KB)</p>
<p>HI all<br>
Attached is a current bibliography of publications that are (relatively) directly related to Go Baby Go modified cars and the various harness systems.</p>
          <p><a href="https://www.gbgconnect.com/t/best-practice-thoughts/43/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://www.gbgconnect.com/t/best-practice-thoughts/43/2</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 18:05:40 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">www.gbgconnect.com-post-43-2</guid>
        <source url="https://www.gbgconnect.com/t/best-practice-thoughts/43.rss">Best Practice Thoughts</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Best Practice Thoughts</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[jacgallo]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Best Practices in my opinion help guide decisions. There may be exceptions but exceptions require additional rationale and critique.</p>
<p>The overall best practice guideline (IMHO) is that <strong>individuals participating in workshop builds (whether 3rd graders, graduate students or corporate event attendees) take PERSONAL RESPONSIBILITY for the cars they modify.</strong><br>
This practice will result in families, children, tools, cars, event attendees and the event location being treated with compassion, care and consideration.</p>
<p>Other Best Practice thoughts:</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p><strong>Cars and attendance at the ‘workshops’ are free to families.</strong><br>
There may be circumstances where groups may have to require families to provide the car and/or parts of the modification kit (PVC, pool noodle etc.) but there should not be a ‘charge’ for the actual modifications.<br>
Certain individuals (examples: clinicians, teachers, admin) may<br>
a) be charged a fee for attendance.<br>
b) gain other perks for attendance - example, continuing education units.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>A mechanical and/or electrical engineer should ‘sign off’ on the modifications.</strong></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Someone with significant knowledge of each child’s abilities should be present</strong> during the build. In addition to family, teacher and/or pediatric therapist are often helpful.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>A group’s initial workshop should be as easy and fun as possible.</strong><br>
This means the simplest cars, the less involved children, the fewer the cars and the less stress the better.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Remind families that mobility is risky.</strong><br>
Both the children and families are gaining meaningful mobility through a modified car.<br>
This mobility may be completely new for them.<br>
A child with a toy car has the ability to move (likely faster, easier and over more ground than ever before) – so keep a constant eye on the driver!</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>When in (even the slightest) doubt about something, simply ask</strong></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Have enough extra hands and eyes</strong><br>
This lessens the stress, increases the fun, gets questions answered and allow each family to be pampered just like they should be!</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Consider the liability.</strong><br>
Different groups address liability differently but all groups should discuss and address the liability of modifying cars.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Use only top quality cars</strong><br>
please seek out information from the other chapters/groups modifying cars as to which cars are low quality and simply do not use them.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Thank those that share their information, and share what you learn!</strong><br>
Go Baby Go spreads rapidly due to the time, effort, compassion and skill of those who join the movement.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Go bigger, build better, share broader!</strong></p>
</li>
</ol>
          <p><a href="https://www.gbgconnect.com/t/best-practice-thoughts/43/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://www.gbgconnect.com/t/best-practice-thoughts/43/1</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 18:34:11 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">www.gbgconnect.com-post-43-1</guid>
        <source url="https://www.gbgconnect.com/t/best-practice-thoughts/43.rss">Best Practice Thoughts</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
