<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Variety of Illinois - Chicago Event?</title>
    <link>https://www.gbgconnect.com/t/variety-of-illinois-chicago-event/508</link>
    <description>Hello!

I work for Variety of Illinois and we&#39;re trying to build an annual Go Baby Go event! I was hoping to put some feelers out and see if anyone had any guidance on people, schools, or organizations that would want to be involved? I&#39;m new to the Chicago area and would love some guidance or tips on engineering schools, organizations and or specific names of people that have shown an interest in an annual Go Baby Go event! 

In addition - does anyone have advice for someone that&#39;s planning a new event? any guidance you wish you would&#39;ve known prior to your first Go Baby Go? 

Thank you!</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 16:37:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>GBG Community Connector</category>
    <atom:link href="https://www.gbgconnect.com/t/variety-of-illinois-chicago-event/508.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Variety of Illinois - Chicago Event?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[jaentzminger]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hello!</p>
<p>I work for Variety of Illinois and we’re trying to build an annual Go Baby Go event! I was hoping to put some feelers out and see if anyone had any guidance on people, schools, or organizations that would want to be involved? I’m new to the Chicago area and would love some guidance or tips on engineering schools, organizations and or specific names of people that have shown an interest in an annual Go Baby Go event!</p>
<p>In addition - does anyone have advice for someone that’s planning a new event? any guidance you wish you would’ve known prior to your first Go Baby Go?</p>
<p>Thank you!</p>
          <p><a href="https://www.gbgconnect.com/t/variety-of-illinois-chicago-event/508/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://www.gbgconnect.com/t/variety-of-illinois-chicago-event/508/1</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 16:37:12 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">www.gbgconnect.com-post-508-1</guid>
        <source url="https://www.gbgconnect.com/t/variety-of-illinois-chicago-event/508.rss">Variety of Illinois - Chicago Event?</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
