<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Greetings fellow GBG&#39;nistas ;)</title>
    <link>https://www.gbgconnect.com/t/greetings-fellow-gbgnistas/26</link>
    <description>Wanted to thank Doc G &amp; the KC crew for setting up this most excellent forum. Excited about the possibilities for greater collaboration this will offer :smile:

For those who havent heard of our efforts, POP (Power of Play) is the next step in the evolution of GoBabyGo-RockyTop from a side project started in 2014 in Knoxville, TN, to a full-blown 501c3 (pending) NPO based on the principle fostering inclusion through adapted play. We realized quickly when we first started building go-bots that the gift of mobility to our kids was the means to an end, but not necessarily the end itself. So now we&#39;re trying to fill in the other pieces of the inclusion &quot;puzzle&quot; ... such as truly inclusive playgrounds, easier access to adapted PE / play equipt for children &amp; adults alike, and working w the concept of &quot;reverse-inclusion&quot; by upcycling abandoned mobility equipt &amp; using it to get people with &amp; without disabilities playing the same game at the same time with the same chance for fun for all ... such as wheelchair soccer and wheelchair basketball.  Our hope is that by creating fun ways to promote the kind of frequent opportunities and close proximity required for social networking to flourish, that true inclusion will be the result ... and that the true power of &quot;It&#39;s not what you know, but WHO you know&quot; will finally be put to work to benefit the lives of people w disabilities :+1:  Be happy to discuss the concept with anyone interested. In the meantime, just glad to be a part of this most excellent adventure sparked by Doc &amp; the gang at UDel.  Can&#39;t wait to see what the future holds ....</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2017 20:45:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>GBG Community Connector</category>
    <atom:link href="https://www.gbgconnect.com/t/greetings-fellow-gbgnistas/26.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Greetings fellow GBG&#39;nistas ;)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[gavin.wood]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>So happy to have you all!!! We noticed that the one thing missing was a way to get all of these amazing people connected with each other. So glad to have more people on the forum!! Your POP organization sounds cool! Congrats and looking forward to seeing what you guys do!</p>
          <p><a href="https://www.gbgconnect.com/t/greetings-fellow-gbgnistas/26/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://www.gbgconnect.com/t/greetings-fellow-gbgnistas/26/2</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2017 20:45:12 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">www.gbgconnect.com-post-26-2</guid>
        <source url="https://www.gbgconnect.com/t/greetings-fellow-gbgnistas/26.rss">Greetings fellow GBG&#39;nistas ;)</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Greetings fellow GBG&#39;nistas ;)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Pete-from-POP]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Wanted to thank Doc G &amp; the KC crew for setting up this most excellent forum. Excited about the possibilities for greater collaboration this will offer <img src="https://discourse-cdn-sjc1.com/standard6/images/emoji/google/smile.png?v=5" title=":smile:" class="emoji" alt=":smile:"></p>
<p>For those who havent heard of our efforts, POP (Power of Play) is the next step in the evolution of GoBabyGo-RockyTop from a side project started in 2014 in Knoxville, TN, to a full-blown 501c3 (pending) NPO based on the principle fostering inclusion through adapted play. We realized quickly when we first started building go-bots that the gift of mobility to our kids was the means to an end, but not necessarily the end itself. So now we’re trying to fill in the other pieces of the inclusion “puzzle” … such as truly inclusive playgrounds, easier access to adapted PE / play equipt for children &amp; adults alike, and working w the concept of “reverse-inclusion” by upcycling abandoned mobility equipt &amp; using it to get people with &amp; without disabilities playing the same game at the same time with the same chance for fun for all … such as wheelchair soccer and wheelchair basketball.  Our hope is that by creating fun ways to promote the kind of frequent opportunities and close proximity required for social networking to flourish, that true inclusion will be the result … and that the true power of “It’s not what you know, but WHO you know” will finally be put to work to benefit the lives of people w disabilities <img src="https://discourse-cdn-sjc1.com/standard6/images/emoji/google/+1.png?v=5" title=":+1:" class="emoji" alt=":+1:">  Be happy to discuss the concept with anyone interested. In the meantime, just glad to be a part of this most excellent adventure sparked by Doc &amp; the gang at UDel.  Can’t wait to see what the future holds …</p>
          <p><a href="https://www.gbgconnect.com/t/greetings-fellow-gbgnistas/26/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://www.gbgconnect.com/t/greetings-fellow-gbgnistas/26/1</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2017 18:24:37 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">www.gbgconnect.com-post-26-1</guid>
        <source url="https://www.gbgconnect.com/t/greetings-fellow-gbgnistas/26.rss">Greetings fellow GBG&#39;nistas ;)</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
