<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Liability issues</title>
    <link>https://www.gbgconnect.com/t/liability-issues/190</link>
    <description>Hello, I work out of the University of Vermont as a statewide PT consultant. We are trying to launch a statewide Early Mobility project, to promote access to early mobility across the state. We have so far worked with a local high school to modify a Wild Thing and have other community partners ready to help modify other cars as well. However, we are now in a holding pattern because our university is worried about the liability involved. We have informed them that we certainly aren&#39;t the first University to be doing this, and have provided many examples, but they want more. Would anyone mind sharing how they cover liability? I saw KC&#39;s liability form here (thank you!), but if anyone could share anything else about their liability journey with their institution it would be greatly appreciated. Thanks! Tamra</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 15:58:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Best Practices</category>
    <atom:link href="https://www.gbgconnect.com/t/liability-issues/190.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Liability issues</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Tamra]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hello, I work out of the University of Vermont as a statewide PT consultant. We are trying to launch a statewide Early Mobility project, to promote access to early mobility across the state. We have so far worked with a local high school to modify a Wild Thing and have other community partners ready to help modify other cars as well. However, we are now in a holding pattern because our university is worried about the liability involved. We have informed them that we certainly aren’t the first University to be doing this, and have provided many examples, but they want more. Would anyone mind sharing how they cover liability? I saw KC’s liability form here (thank you!), but if anyone could share anything else about their liability journey with their institution it would be greatly appreciated. Thanks! Tamra</p>
          <p><a href="https://www.gbgconnect.com/t/liability-issues/190/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://www.gbgconnect.com/t/liability-issues/190/1</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 15:58:19 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">www.gbgconnect.com-post-190-1</guid>
        <source url="https://www.gbgconnect.com/t/liability-issues/190.rss">Liability issues</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
